Our favorite fifth bestie in the world,
the one, the only Brad Bersner from
Altimter. Brad has had unbelievable
career starting five companies. So, he's
got a very different mentality than your
sort of classic hedge fund guy.
>> He's an amazingly successful guy and
he's put up a tremendous amount of
money.
>> Every child in America, all 70 million
kids under the age of 18 deserve to have
one of these accounts. This would not be
a law if Brad Gerster did not pursue it
with absolute dogged determination.
>> This is not a program. This is a
platform. It is the largest unlock of
direct philanthropy in the history of
the country.
>> I think the antidote to more socialism
is more capitalism.
Please welcome Brad Gersner.
Woo.
Wow.
Let's go.
Thank you guys. And thank you for so
much love yesterday, especially on the
Trump accounts. So many people came up.
Everybody gets what this means for
America. We're in a battle for the soul
of America. 70 million kids are going to
be made direct owners in America. That
is how we beat the scourge of capital or
socialism. We make every child a
capitalist.
>> And also
thank you to all the people yesterday
who came up who took the CAC scan, the
heart scan outside from the center for
heart attack prevention which we
started. There's no doubt based on these
results we uh you know we're going to
save some lives even yesterday. Okay.
This is the highest ROI thing you can do
in healthcare. Every cardiologist I talk
to does this for themselves, their
family, and their friends. It's a
hundred bucks, 15 minutes. Get it done.
If we turn this into the mammogram for
the heart, we'll save 50,000 lives a
year in this country. It's like ending a
Ukraine war in America every year. So,
go get your CAC scan done if you have
it. But today is not about those two
moonshots.
Today is kind of a throwback to what I
used to do on the pod with these guys,
which is a market check, a tech check,
state of the market. Where are we? Where
are we going? What do we have to believe
to be true in order for the market to
continue to work? We're going to do a
bit of a speed round here. So, bear with
me. Get your cameras out. Get your notes
out. Some good some good chart candy in
here for you guys. So markets up 15%
this year, up 39% since January of last
year, despite all the concerns about
tariffs, despite all the concerns about
geopolitics,
despite all the concerns about AI
regulation.
The scoreboard, we have a lot of people
in the bestie group who said gold was
going to be off the charts this year.
It's flat. Bitcoin's down 10%. But look,
we have Nvidia revenue up 2x.
Hyperscaler capex up 2x. Open AI and
Enthropics valuation up 2x. SpaceX up
two and a halfx in a pretty nasty
backdrop.
This is not about multiple expansion.
This is an earnings driven market
expansion. We've seen multiple
contraction this year. Earnings are up
26% of course driven a lot by AI
infrastructure, but the multiple on the
NASDAQ and the S&P is actually down.
Look at Nvidia trading at 14 times next
year's fully taxed gap earnings. This is
no bubble like it was in 2000.
NASDAQ, S&P, Socks, Nvidia, all trading
well below their average multiples.
Okay, MAG 7 basically in line with its
average multiple, but not everybody is
winning. Okay, at the bottom here,
consumer discretionary, software,
financials, huge sections of the market
have barely moved, right? This is a
market that is being driven by the
largest capex buildout, the largest
super cycle in the history of
technology.
Semiconductors are 70% of the NASDAQ's
return.
70% of the return. That's both good and
bad, and we'll get into that.
So, who's making the money? The makers
of the tokens are making the money and
the buyers of the tokens are basically
going along for the ride
because of the tightness in the
infrastructure market. We have massive
public companies that look like venture
capital returns.
Dell up 5x up 9x in just 18 months.
I love this chart. In blue you have the
hyperscaler capex.
In orange you have the free cash flow of
the semiconductor companies. Do you
notice anything?
Their capex is almost dollar fordoll
free cash flow to the infrastructure
companies.
Okay. Where were we at the start of the
year? This is a really important
framework to get your head around. You
may remember a certain podcast I did
with Sam Alman and Satcha in October of
last year. And I asked Sam a very basic
question that was on everybody's mind.
How can you commit to a trillion dollars
in capex when you have $13 billion of
gap revenue?
I thought this would be a way to clear
up some confusion in the market.
Instead, he told me to sell my shares.
But then in the beginning of December we
have opus 4.5 and claude code and then
in January anthropics revenue was two
billion and then in February it's 4
billion and in March it was 11 billion.
Do you notice anything that happened
there in March? People started figuring
out what anthropics revenue was. We had
a an exclamation point answer to the
question will the AI revenue showed up?
It showed up in a massive way and that's
why we got this historic run in April
and May. We ripped off the bottom
because the fuse was lit by Anthropic's
monthly revenue. And then in in June and
July, we had some consolidation. Why?
Because Anthropic came out and said,
"Oh, our annual run rate revenue is 65."
People thought it was 75. So they had to
revise down their estimates a little
bit. And we had some concerns about open
source. Is open source catching up? you
know, is Anthropic going to continue to
be able to generate those revenues? And
so, we've kind of moved sideways since
then.
It's hard to get your head around the
fact that these revenues have never
happened before in the history of
capitalism,
right? We are on parabolic double
exponential curves around these
revenues. So the collective run rate,
let's just call it of the top three
labs, Anthropic, Open AI, and SpaceX is
about a hundred billion based upon all
the rumors that are out there coming out
of July.
I think they need to collectively get to
at least $180 billion by the end of the
year, add another $80 billion across
those three labs just to keep the AI
trade intact.
So this is the single most important
data point in the market today, right?
Is Anthropics monthly revenue is
OpenAI's monthly revenue going to be 4
billion or 8 billion? It's almost hard
to get your head around. Most of us
who've been in venture capital for a
long time, if you added a billion, if
you got to a billion dollars in software
revenue over like four or five years,
you were in the top 5% of software
companies. But this is what the world is
now pricing in. So why is this so
important? It's this slide. If you're
going to build a a trillion half dollars
a year in capex, somebody has to pay for
it, right? Microsoft's not paying for
it. They're building it to rent it.
Google's not paying for it. They're
building it to rent it. Amazon's
building it to rent it. Well, who is the
person renting it? We have to have the
offtake revenues in order to pay that
rent. So if we exit this year around,
you know, let's call it 200 billion of
run rate revenue. That's below the the
years there. I think you have to go from
200 to 450 to 800 or a trillion dollars
just to keep up. The blue bar is the
expected capex just from the MAG 5 and
the orange bar is the offtake revenue,
the gap offtake revenue that we need to
see in order to keep this trade intact
over the course of the next few years.
Otherwise, we can't build this much
capex.
So, the labs are increasingly,
you know, like the conversation I had
with Sam last October, they're
aggressively expanding compute. Why? All
the things you heard yesterday, we're
heading into recursive cycles. They're
seeing, you know, incredible demand for
the product. And so, they're building
out compute. This year the total amount
of uh compute added so 2026 about 19
gawatt and about seven of those
gigawatts went to the two leading labs.
Next year this is semi analysis so Dylan
Patel forecast that the work that we're
going to add 43 gawatt and that about 14
gawatt are going to go to the leading
labs and we'll come back to this
question of can we really stand up 43
gawatts of compute next year. Notice
that the amount that we're adding next
year is as much as the total compute we
have in the United States this year, the
cumulative compute we have in the United
States this year. So that's what the
market is anticipating.
What happens if that doesn't happen? And
by the way, if you added those bars up,
by 2028, to David Sax's point yesterday,
over half of the total compute in the
country is controlled by two labs.
So it does the TAM exist? Does the TAM
exist? Right? So if we look at the total
TAM of knowledge work, right? That this
is a massive massive category. You got
consumer plus ads plus coding and all
these white collar workflows, millions
of enterprises. I would argue it's the
largest TAM in the history of the world.
You only have to get to about 4% of that
TAM or 1.2 trillion in order to pay for
the capex. So I don't think it's a TAM
issue. Um, obviously Jensen was on our
was on the pod and he he he talked two
years ago that inference was going to 1
billionx and remember all the people
saying he's full of there's no way this
can 1 billionx. That's exactly what
we've done in the a age of agents,
right? We've had this exponential token
growth this year. 47 quadrillion tokens
that are going to be produced. So it's
not a question again of demand. Codeex
users have grown 40x in the last eight
months and knowledge work at enterprises
if you look at the median amount that
enterprises are spending about 17x over
the course of the last 18 months and
I've talked to many people in the
audience here small businesses medium
businesses large businesses businesses
like alimter we can't operate our
business without buying AI so this is
not overly surprising to me and when we
think about the productivity dividend to
the economy me. You know, if you look at
2015 to 2025, EPS growth was about 10%.
That was 6% revenue plus about 38 bips
of margin expansion every year out of
the NASDAQ. So, here's the question. Can
we turn the 38 bips to 100 bips of
margin expansion because of AI? The
answer is obviously yes. Every company I
talk to, Uber says we're going to grow
20%, we're not going to grow headcount.
Snowflake says we're going to grow 30%,
we're not going to grow headcount.
That's what's happening. That is margin
expansion. The single largest cost input
to every one of these companies are
humans and engineers. It's not that
they're going to fire everybody. They're
just not going to hire them at the rate
that they hired him before. And then of
course, we're going to have consumer
agents in everybody's pocket. You may
remember this bet I had with Bill. You
know, when are we going to be able to
book a hotel using your consumer agent
in your pocket? I think we've just
gotten that with Muse and with Instinct.
This could be another trillion dollar
category, but it's definitely going to
consume massive tokens. Here are the
three risks and challenges. And sorry
I'm going so quick, but I want to keep
it keep it moving. Regulation. We heard
a lot about this yesterday. Power. And
then what's going on with interest
rates? So, you know, this is the
regulation tugof-war,
right? Um, and I I've heard from a lot
of people, they're like, you're on both
sides of the issue. Here's the fact,
okay, the answer is not going to be on
one end or the other. We're going to
have to have common sense, pragmatic
solutions that get my mom, my sister,
and the br brother off the cliff, right?
We need to give comfort and confidence
to the people who elect our
representatives that it's safe. And so,
you heard Elon yesterday give a great
suggestion around peer review. So, I'm
confident that we're going to get there,
but it's kind of messy the sausage
making along the way. But we have a
prior history of excess regulation. When
people get scared, when activists start
pushing an agenda, we shut down 67
fision reactors in this country. We
unilaterally disarmed against China.
It's been a disaster for the country.
Right? All the clean energy we could
have gotten. Instead, we've gotten
non-clean emissions because we had a
group of activists who were hellbent on
shutting down nuclear. can't allow this
to occur to AI.
So regulation's a threat. It's a risk.
Atoms and energy are hard. So getting
back to can we stand up 43 gawatt of
compute. Our total compute in the
country is less than 40 gawatt. Doing
this in one year, we've got to overcome
permitting and local opposition. You
guys see all of that. grid
interconnection delays, skilled labor
shortages, power equipment is sold out.
It's the largest buildout in the history
of the country. I would suggest Dylan's
forecast to 43 gawatt next year is too
aggressive. I don't think we're going to
get there. I think the total amount
we're actually going to stand up is
somewhere closer to 25 gawatt. And I
think of that 25 gawatt, half of it will
be for anthropic and open AI.
Um I think that's enough to generate the
revenue. Remember Anthropics revenue
reportedly this year 100 billion 110
billion. If they do that they're doing
it with a gigawatt and a half of
compute. So if they add another four or
five gawatts of compute that's certainly
enough to add another 100 billion in
revenue. So I don't think we need more
gigawatts to get to the revenue targets
for next year. But this is my hunch that
we're not going to get to the 43.
And then of course we're going to hear
more tomorrow. I think rate hikes are
coming. I think it's now over 90% chance
that we're going to have rate hikes
tomorrow. Why does this matter? Because
all of this now borrowed money, right?
We're borrowing money in order to stand
up these data centers. So the hurdle
rate for that money is going up. And um
so that's not only a challenge for data
centers, but remember, you know, as
Warren Buffett says that, you know,
interest rates are to stocks what
gravity is to matter,
right? Right? If you can earn 5 1.5 or
6% on your money without taking equity
risk, then you know it's going to be a
challenge for stocks. So, here's where I
think we are and we're going to end on
this slide and and then then we'll bring
the guys out and chop it up a little
bit. But this is the flight path. This
is how I think about managing the
portfolio, right? We're up about the
NASDAQ's up about 15%. But as I sit here
and think about the risk, do I want to
be small, medium, or large? This is how
I think about the fan of potential
outcomes. If the monthly AI lab revenues
are closer to that$8 billion number, I
think it's takeoff. Okay. I think we are
going to see an IPO this year. Um, and
so I'm paying very close attention to
what in fact are those monthly revenue
numbers. I think the trends are intact,
but we will see. That's going to be the
single most important thing as to
whether or not uh between now and the
end of the year uh we we have liftoff.
Second one is rates, the election, oil
prices. Obviously, rates are following
oil prices to a certain extent. So, what
happens there? You know, if rates were
to go to five and a half on the 10-year,
that's going to be a big burden uh you
know, on on the equity market. Then
finally, the regulation, the anthropic
IPO, we saw a trade down yesterday
because people are concerned that maybe
we're going to have a halt or or
postponement. That would obviously be a
major issue. I don't think that's going
to happen, but again, that would be a
concern. So that's the fan of potential
outcomes. From here we're up 15%.
I think we could go higher uh you know
through the balance of the year. Uh or
we could go lower. I'll leave you with
this.
The period of 2023 to 2025, you only had
to get one thing right. That AI was
going to be the biggest super cycle in
the history of technology. And you
needed to shove your chips into the AI
trade. That's it. Right? If you were in
the AI trade, you made money. That is
not where we are in 2026. Everybody
knows about AI. It's all priced now.
It's about facts and circumstances. Stay
mentally flexible. Follow the facts.
Don't yolo. Okay? Don't go forex like
our friend up north who uh gave all his
money to Citadel, right? Um Forex
levered in this market, you know, very
dangerous. So, in my estimation, we're
medium position. We're mentally
flexible. If we see those revenues come
in big for these next few months and we
see oil prices retreat, we're going to
put more chips on the table. If not,
we'll, you know, we'll reserve the right
to go even smaller. With that, thank you
all. Thanks for having me.